It has been one year since Sir Rio
and Latifa came to our village.
I'm sure everyone is aware of how much
the two of them have done for us here.
So on this fine day of
the Grand Spirit Festival,
with the kiss of blessing from Lady Dryas,
Sir Rio is hereby welcomed as our sworn friend,
and Latifa as a resident of our village.
I'm going to continue to
count on the both of you.
Yes, milady!
Y-Yes, milady!
Now, that's the end of the ceremony.
Everyone! It's time to feast!
Yeah!
Seirei Gensouki
Festival Night
How...
did things turn out like this?
Mashter Rio, are you enjoying yourshelf?
Miss Orphia, perhaps you
should refrain a little...
Oh, how long're you gonna
shpeak sho formally with ush?
What?
It'sh already been a year shince
we met. It'sh unforgivable!
Orphia, don't be ridiculous.
Master Rio is right.
Miss Sara...
Clinging to him like this is just...
Sara, I think you might be drunk yourself.
Yes, just a little.
It's not just a little. I'm certain of it.
Big Sis Orphia! Big Sis Sara! That's no fair!
L-Latifa! I can't breathe!
Big Sister Sara, Big Sister Orphia...
Master Rio looks to be at a loss.
I know you want to deepen your
friendship with Master Rio,
but you're causing him problems instead.
Deepen their friendship with me?
That'sh right! I wanna be
friendlier with you, Mashter Rio!
We live together, don't we?
B-But... How can I put this...
Latifa treats us as her older sisters,
but it feels like you keep your
distance from us, Master Rio.
And even now, when you've
become our sworn friend...
Thank you.
I'm not very good at being social, but...
if you'd let me be better friends
with you, it would make me very happy.
O-Of course! We'd be delighted!
Please, think well of us!
Yay!
Now we can get along even better
with everyone than we did before!
Yes.
Well, if we're going to
exchange cups of friendship,
I'm going to go get more to drink!
What? No, I think...
It would be better if we didn't!
I'm gonna go bring shome.
The both of you are getting tipsy. I'll go.
I'll go, too!
She seems to be having fun.
Mistress Ursula...
Yes. She has a lovely smile.
She has become an integral
part of our village.
I'm... thinking I should tell Latifa soon.
So you are going, then?
Yes.
She is sure to miss you.
I see.
I feel it is a little too soon,
but perhaps it is the right time.
Tonight, we shall rest here. We'll depart
for Strahl early tomorrow morning.
I'm going to investigate the area a little.
Please, look after the griffin.
What? But...
Here. Just in case.
It's a type of artifact.
Protection, in the event the worst happens.
If you swallow this, I will
be able to tell where you are.
I-I see.
If anything happens,
don't worry about me.
Use the griffin to escape.
If you head in that direction,
it will be easier for me to find you.
Please, take very good care of the egg.
It's just about time for you to
come after the egg, I believe.
And I see you've made your appearance.
I do hope my lure plays his role to his utmost.
What's wrong, Onii-chan?
You asked me to go on a walk, but you
haven't said anything this whole time.
Sorry.
Let's go back to the plaza!
There's still lots of food and drink left!
Latifa...
What is it?
Do you enjoy living here?
Yes! It's really fun!
Big Sis Sara and the others are here.
And Mistress Ursula and the
others are really nice.
And... you're here, Onii-chan!
I see.
Yup!
Latifa.
After a little while, I...
I'm... going to leave the village.
What?
No.
You know that I was originally
headed to the east, right?
I'm going with you.
I can't take you with me.
Why not?
I'm going somewhere I've never
been before. I don't know the dangers.
No! I don't want to be apart from you, ever!
Latifa...
I don't want to hear it!
Latifa!
A reaction inside the barrier?
Yes. Lady Dryas noticed it, too.
It seems it isn't simply one or two.
I will go confirm it immediately.
Take warriors with you.
Yes, Eldest.
It seems everyone went,
leaving no one behind.
Your faculties of pursuit are impressive,
but it seems your intelligence
is somewhat lacking.
Thanks to that, I can take
my time acquiring these.
Sara, I'm detecting suspicious od reactions.
Location?
Two at that spring.
There's a human!
And...
A griffin!
Be careful that we're not the ones
to initiate combat. Understood?
Understood!
Master Reiss—
Demi-humans!
Will you come quietly and do as we say?
What are you doing here at this time of day?
Is that... What kind of egg is that?
Th-This is, um...
Please, answer us.
Halt!
Go!
Lady Sara, permission to attack?
It seems it's unavoidable.
Target the griffin!
That way is...
He's headed toward the village!
Hey! We're running away! Go faster!
Lady Sara!
It's a flight of wyverns!
Why have wyverns come to a place like this?
Could it be the egg that boy has?
We can't allow him to enter the village!
Orphia! Alma!
We'll handle the black wyvern.
Uzuma and the rest of you,
take the other wyverns!
Understood!
Take word to Mistress Ursula and the others!
Now, then, as his role is over...
Farewell.
Alma, please take care of the black wyvern.
Understood!
Big Sister Sara, will you
lend me your bond spirit?
I'll have it fight alongside my Ifritah!
All right.
Hel!
I'm... going to leave the village.
No.
I can't take you with me.
No, I don't want that. I don't want it! No!
A-Are you all right?
What's going on?
An egg?
Quickly, evacuate! Take shelter!
Please, hurry!
Has something happened?
Oh, Rio. The festival has been canceled.
Canceled?
A flight of wyverns is approaching.
Wyverns?
It seems like Sara and the others are
holding them off above the forest for now,
but they may soon be upon us.
The forest?
Onii-chan!
Latifa!
No!
Big Sis Alma!
Why are you here?
Ifritah!
Latifa, please stay back!
Big Sis Alma!
You can't beat it! Let's run away!
I can't!
At this rate, the wyverns
will reach the village!
The village?
If I can buy some time...
Over here!
This way!
Latifa! Don't!
I'm a part of the village, too!
Latifa!
Come on! I'm over here!
Latifa, just buy a little time!
We'll switch places on my command!
Right!
Latifa!
Onii-chan!
I'm sorry I took so long, Latifa.
I-It's fine!
I'm the one who's sorry,
since I ran off like that...
We can talk later.
Everything's fine now. You can stand down.
He's battling a black wyvern
with his bare hands?
Onii-chan!
I-Incredible!
He defeated that black wyvern so easily!
It seems the inside of its
mouth was a weak spot.
Master Rio? And Latifa, too?
That's amazing, Alma!
You defeated the black wyvern?
No, it was Master Rio who
defeated it single-handedly.
Single-handedly?
Are there wounded?
Fortunately, we took care of
things without a single casualty.
I wonder why the other wyverns retreated.
It must be because this
black wyvern was defeated.
Wyverns are timid by nature. They won't
challenge those they know they can't beat.
This is all thanks to Master Rio!
Thank you so much!
I am...
your sworn friend, after all.
Onii-chan!
I'm... sorry about last night.
No, it's my fault.
There must have been a better
way for me to tell you.
The truth is... I already knew.
I knew you might leave
one day, Onii-chan.
I was... really scared.
Scared?
Because I've only ever caused
trouble for you, Onii-chan.
I thought that's why you might leave one day.
I wondered if I was a hindrance to you.
You're not troublesome or a hindrance to me.
You're my little sister, right, Latifa?
Onii-chan... are you sure?
You really don't mind having
a little sister like me?
I...
I really want to be your
little sister, Onii-chan!
You're the person who saved me,
who treated me so kindly...
I want to be your little sister!
It's only that I didn't want to kill anyone.
I didn't want to dirty my hands.
You're wrong!
It's real!
Onii-chan, your kindness is real!
Thank you.
You know...
If you really hate it that much, Latifa...
No, it's fine!
I'll work hard.
And I'm sure we'll meet again someday.
I'm heading east...
toward the Yagumo region,
but I never told you why, did I?
No.
It's the land my late parents came from.
That's why I want to try going there.
This is the first time you've told me
anything about yourself, Onii-chan.
I guess it is.
There's something I want to tell you, too.
I don't know if you'll believe me, but...
The thing is, I died once.
And I used to be human.
I was reincarnated and
became the person I am now.
I was in a place called Japan before.
I see.
You believe me?
I do. Because I'm the same.
What?
I was a Japanese person
just like you, Latifa.
What?
Actually, it might have been better
if I'd confided in you before.
It's just that, in the beginning,
your mental state wasn't very stable,
so I thought it better not to tell you.
No. The truth is, I didn't
want to say anything.
I felt like it would raise lingering
regrets from when I was Japanese.
I see.
Onii-chan was Japanese, just like me.
Did those regrets appear?
If I said "no," I'd be lying.
But I swore that I would be
strong and survive this world.
That's another reason I want
to go to Yagumo at least once.
Yes. I'll get stronger, too!
I'll be here waiting for you
to come home, Onii-chan!
Thank you...
Latifa.
Thank you for everything.
I never imagined you would do
me the honor of seeing me off.
Quit talking like we're strangers!
This is from us dwarfs.
The sword is made of mithril,
so it can absorb your spirit arts
and cloak itself in them.
The armor is made from the hide
of the black wyvern you defeated.
Its defensive strength will make you think
metal armor is no better than paper.
Thank you very much.
From the elves, there are secret
medicines and wondrous elixirs.
From the beast peoples, foodstuffs and drink.
With so much, carrying it all
with me will be a little...
Sir Rio, please take this.
Is that... a space-time cache?
I couldn't possibly accept
something so precious!
It is proof that you are a sworn friend.
With this, your travels should
be considerably easier.
It's fine! Please, take it!
Thank you very much.
Go ahead and put your baggage
in the space-time cache.
Storage!
If the unthinkable happens, and this
village of the spirits faces danger,
as your sworn friend,
I promise I will come running.
Onii-chan, have a good trip!
I'll be back.
Thank you for everything you did for me!
It is we who thank you!
Safe travels.
Take care.
Take care of Latifa... of my little sister.
Leave it to us!
See you later, Onii-chan!
Then...
Have a good trip!
Onii-chan, stay safe!
Stay... safe...
Hup!
No other letters have come since then.
Are you okay, Rio?
Next Time
Land of Promises
"Land of Promises."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
There's
something
I want to talk
to you about,
Onii-chan.
By Minazuki Futago
Okay...
She's
probably
going to
say she
used to be
Japanese...
What do
you think
we're going
to have
for dinner
today?
Huh?
growl